FreshLedger turns receipts into freshness-aware inventory.
GPT-5.6 Sol in Codex built it almost end to end.
We began with a product idea and non-negotiable safety rules.
The agent read the specification, designed the Expo, FastAPI, and SQLite architecture,
and implemented this receipt-to-ledger spine.
Local OCR returns five editable items from the photo with no cloud call.
GPT-5.6 Sol also built strict grounding: an item must match our shelf-life reference
before receiving advice.
One confirmation saves the receipt and ranks the pantry by urgency,
with conservative storage guidance.
The agent then implemented rescue meals and exact, integer-cent waste accounting.
Raw chicken is most urgent; tossing it records exactly $9.44
and regenerates the recommendations from persisted inventory.
Codex connected all five promised features, while GPT-5.6 Sol traced bugs
across the client, API, database, and safety rules.
The grocery story now turns real events into spending, waste,
category breakdowns, and next-trip advice.
During adversarial review, GPT-5.6 Sol found duplicate-import, stale-advice,
compound-food, cache, and concurrency failures, then converted them into regression tests and fixes.
The result blocks this duplicate and keeps paper towels out of the food pantry.
With two receipts, FreshLedger prioritizes orange juice
and proposes meals from actual inventory.
Each suggestion names what it rescues and includes safety notes.
Choosing I made this opens an ingredient-level confirmation;
one atomic update consumes the smoothie items and refreshes every downstream view.
Codex also generated fixtures and tests that verify identity, prices,
reconciliation, and storage clamping across three standing receipts.
Finally, tossing the eggs raises tracked waste to $14.63,
so advice updates from history.
GPT-5.6 Sol was FreshLedger's primary implementation engine through Codex,
driving architecture, code, tests, debugging, and review fixes.
This zero-cloud demo runs Local OCR; the optional GPT-5.6 vision path
uses the same strict Structured Outputs contract.